Finding Aid for Miller, Canfield, Paddock, and Stone records, 1902-1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Miller, Canfield, Paddock, and Stone records
1902-1971
Miller, Canfield, Paddock, and Stone (Firm)
86979 Bb 2; BB oversize
Detroit law firm; minute books of various client businesses and philanthropic organizations; financial records; case logs; title opinions and abstracts.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
71 volumes
2 folders in 19 boxes
2 oversize volumes
The records came from the firm (donor no. 7276 ) in two accessions, 1986 and 2001.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Miller, Canfield, Paddock, and Stone is an international law firm. One of their offices is in Detroit, Michigan.
The record group includes minute books and other records of client businesses and philanthropic organizations. These include land and realty organizations, notably the Palms Realty Co. and the Ernst Kern Co. There are also financial records of the firm, including registers containing billing records and case activity logs; record of hours; and volumes of title opinions and abstracts.
Subjects:
Business records--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)--Commerce.; Endowments.; Charities--Michigan--Detroit.; Miller, Canfield, Paddock, and Stone (Firm); Real estate business--Michigan.; Law firms--Michigan--Detroit.
Contributors:
Ernst Kern Company.; Michigan Yale-Phillips Educational Corporation.; Palms Realty Company.; Social Research Foundation.
- Client Records
  - Palms Realty Co. minute books, 1913-1958; 4 volumes; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Ernst Kern Co. minute books, 1956-1959; 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Stackpole Fund minute books, 1949-1971; 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Earl Crest Land Co, minute book, 1925-1932; 1 volumes (Box 2)
  - Ward Redwood Co. record book, 1937-1939; 1 volumes (Box 2)
  - Social Research Foundation record book, 1957-1964; 1 volumes (Box 2)
  - Michigan Yale-Phillips Educational Corp. record book, 1942-1957; 1 volumes (Box 2)
  - Riordan Bros. (?) purchase records, 1961-1968 (Box 3)
  - Grosse Pointe Realty Co.
    - Records of loans to, 1920s (Box 3)
    - Financial record book, circa 1925-1938 (Box 3)
- Firm financial records
  - Journal, 1923-1926 (Volume 1)
  - Ledger, 1923-1926 (Volume 2)
  - Registers containing billing records and case activity logs, 14 volumes
    - Miscellaneous clients, 1902-1924 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous clients, 1902-1924 (Box 5)
      (continued)
    - Miscellaneous clients, 1902-1924 (Box 6)
    - Detroit Trust Co., 1912-1925; 4 volumes (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous realty records (mostly Detroit Bank), 1948-1960; 7 volumes (Box 8)
  - Sidney Trowbridge Miller, Jr. personal financial records, 2 volumes (Box 9)
- Other Records
  - Record of Hours, 1932/1933-1933/1934; 2 volumes (Box 9)
  - Record of Hours, 1935/36-1942; 4 volumes (Box 10)
    (missing 1937-1938)
  - Law Registers/case logs, 1904-1916; 4 volumes (Box 11)
  - Law Registers/case logs, 1916-1924/1925; 5 volumes (Box 12)
- Title Opinions and Abstracts
  - 1912-1919, 2 volumes (Box 13)
  - 1919-1920 (Box 14)
  - (various), 1930s-1940 (Box 14)
  - 1941-1942, 2 volumes (Box 15)
  - 1942-1945, 2 volumes (Box 16)
  - 1945-1947, 2 volumes (Box 17)
  - 1947-1948, 2 volumes (Box 18)
  - 1948-1949, 2 volumes (Box 19)